字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
There, there.
來…
Battleships approaching!
喂，戰艦來了！
Notify Lord Gorm!
通知哥魯姆大人
Wait a minute. Look again.
等一下，看清楚
Those are Askeladd's ships.
那些是阿謝拉特的船
Finally home to the village.
終於回到村子了
Good God. We've survived another year.
真是的，我們又活過了一年
You've evaded death once again, Bjorn.
表倫，你又逃過死劫了
We've completed quite the journey.
我們這次跑了滿遠的
Hey, there's sheep!
喂，有羊！
They're still letting them graze?
他們還在放牧嗎？
They're trying to fatten them up a bit.
他們想把羊養胖一點
It seems old man Gorm is as greedy as ever.
看來哥魯姆叔叔還是很吝嗇
Bastards, you did well once again this year.
你們這群混蛋今年還是表現得很好
Enjoy the winter to the fullest!
盡情享受冬天吧！
That way!
那邊！
NOVEMBER 1012 A.D.
（西元1012年11月）
VILLAGE OF FEUDAL LORD GORM JUTLAND PENINSULA
（丹麥日德蘭半島 地方領主哥魯姆的村子）
Look at all that treasure.
看看這些寶藏
I heard they won a great victory in the land of the Franks.
聽說在法蘭克人的地盤大贏了一場
I'd expect no less from Askeladd!
不愧是阿謝拉特
I heard many died this year.
聽說今年也死了很多人
Really?
真的嗎？
I wonder if he'll recruit new crewmen.
不知道他會不會招募新的船員
Damn, I'm excited!
可惡，我好興奮
If I sailed, it'd have to be on Askeladd's ship!
我如果要出海的話 就非搭阿謝拉特的船不可
Idiot.
笨蛋
You'd last three days and die.
你只撐得了三天
Wait a minute. Apologize.
站住，向我道歉
-Here we go. -Yes.
-來了 -好
Ready, and…
準備…
Askeladd!
-阿謝拉特大人！
Welcome home!
-歡迎回家！
Hello there, ladies!
姑娘們
Aren't you cute?
妳們真可愛
Here. I've brought you some fine accessories.
來，我帶了漂亮的首飾回來給妳們
I want a ring!
我要戒指！
Old man Gorm,
哥魯姆叔叔
the girls here aren't shy, but it's actually quite nice!
這裡的女人一點都不害羞，真不錯
Stop talking about girls and get serious.
別說那些了，講正經事吧
Are you even listening?
你有沒有在聽？
Listen, each crewman's daily provisions cost one and a quarter silver coins.
聽好，船員每天的補給品 要花費1.25枚銀幣
You've got 97 crewmen,
一共有97個人
so that's 121 coins.
加起來就是121.25枚銀幣
You're still doing the accounting?
又在算帳？
The price of pigs increased this year.
今年豬的價格漲了
If you eat pork every day, it costs even more.
你們每天都吃豬肉的話，就更花錢了
With the extra cost of beer
啤酒錢另算
and the lodging and firewood expenses added in--
再加上住宿費和柴火費…
Don't worry, old man. Our earnings were excellent this year.
叔叔，別擔心，我們今年賺很多
Give me and my men plenty of food and liquor.
給我的手下們足夠的食物和酒
I'll pay you.
我會付錢的
That's just what I wanted to hear. I'll give you a drink.
我就是想聽這句話
Bring the celebratory wine.
喂，把慶祝用的酒拿來
We have that good wine, right? Bring that.
不是有高級紅酒嗎？去拿來
One, two, three…
一、二、三…
Old man, you really like money that much?
叔叔，你就這麼愛錢？
Does anyone hate it?
有人討厭嗎？
Money is good. Just looking at it lifts my spirits.
錢很好啊，光是用看的就心情好
Hordaland! What are you doing?
喂，荷薩蘭特，妳在做什麼？
Hurry up and bring the wine.
快去拿酒來
Yes.
是
Dear me. What a troublesome woman.
真是的，這女人好難使喚
That slave girl has a strange name.
那個女奴隸名字好奇怪
"Hordaland."
荷薩蘭特
Her name is a region in Norway?
那不是挪威的地名嗎？
Yeah. I bought her recently.
對，我最近買來的
Her father was a lord, but her family was ruined after losing in a war.
好像是領主家的大小姐 戰後就家破人亡了
The girl was expensive because of her beauty.
長得漂亮，所以價錢可貴了
But she's a poor head for work.
不過她辦事不力
Good grief. Being waited on all her life has made her prideful and useless.
真是的，她從小養尊處優 所以個性傲慢，派不上用場
By the way, old man.
對了，叔叔
Would you be a witness for me?
你能當我的見證人嗎？
I've got a duel to settle before dinner.
有人約我在晚餐前決鬥
A duel?
決鬥？
By the way, it's not her fault she's useless.
對了，她沒用不是她的錯
You're just bad at using her.
是你不會用人
What did you say?
你說什麼？
No matter who it is,
不管是誰
you can always use them if you know how.
如果你知道怎麼用人，那誰都好用
Hurry!
快點！
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
They said it's a duel!
他們說有人要決鬥！
Come on, kid!
孩子，加油！
-Kill him! -You can do it!
-殺了他！ -別輸！
And now, in the name of Odin,
在奧丁神的見證下
the duel between Thorfinn and Askeladd will now ensue.
托爾芬與阿謝拉特的決鬥即將開始
Each may have a weapon of his choosing.
武器可各自選擇
If they fight with honor,
只要打得光明磊落
in the case of death, the dead will be welcomed at the gates of Valhalla.
瓦爾哈拉的大門必將為死者敞開
Seriously?
真的嗎？
He was part of Askeladd's crew?
他是阿謝拉特軍團的人？
Then I'm certainly worthy of joining his crew.
那我肯定也夠格搭上他的船吧
Isn't he kind of cute?
他滿可愛的，不是嗎？
What?
什麼？
Askeladd's much richer and stronger.
阿謝拉特更有錢，也更強
Furthermore, the reason for the duel is for Thorfinn to avenge his father.
此外，決鬥的理由是托爾芬為父報仇
Do either of you have any objections?
雙方是否有異議？
No.
沒有
Then begin!
那麼決鬥開始！
That Thorfinn never hesitates, does he?
那個托爾芬永遠不死心吧？
You've… gotten taller.
你長高了耶
How old are you now?
你幾歲了？
Back then, you were only this tall--
那時候你才這麼高…
-He's fast! -Thorfinn went first!
-好快！ -托爾芬先攻了！
He's right at his chest!
直接往胸口攻！
You should at least humor your elders
長輩說話…
when they're talking!
要聽啊！
-He stood up! -He's perfectly fine!
-他站起來了！ -他完全沒事！
He blew him away with one strike.
揮一次劍就能把人砍飛
Don't be ridiculous. Thorfinn jumped.
少來了，是托爾芬跳開了
At close range, he knows his daggers are advantageous.
他知道短劍用近距離攻擊比較有利
He's grown strong.
他變強了
That's it, kid!
幹得好，孩子！
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
Kill him!
殺了他！
He's got it!
機會來了！
Damn it.
可惡
That's it!
就是這樣！
Get him!
抓住他！
Just a little more, kid!
孩子，再加把勁！
You know, Thorfinn.
托爾芬
Your father…
你爸…
Wait, what was his name again?
等等，他叫什麼來著？
Let's see. Tho…
我想想，托…
Tho… Tho…
托…
Thors!
托爾茲！
Thors! That's right.
托爾茲，沒錯
It's no use. I've grown forgetful in my old age.
真是糟糕，我年紀大了很健忘
But, you know,
不過啊
I'm sorry to bring it up in the middle of your fight for revenge,
是說你正在報仇 我說這句話很不好意思
but I've killed dozens of men.
但我殺了很多人
I don't remember your father.
已經不記得你爸了
Did I really kill him?
我真的殺了他嗎？
This "Thoril."
這位“托利爾”先生
Now,
喂
how exactly did I kill him?
我是怎麼殺死他的？
Could you perhaps have misunderstood something?
會不會是你誤會了什麼？
Bastard.
混蛋
If you had fought fairly,
如果你打得光明正大
my father would have never lost.
我爸才不可能會輸
Back then, you used me.
那時候你利用我…
You used me as a hostage!
你利用我當人質！
Oh, now I remember!
這下我想起來了
He was the idiot who threw away his sword in exchange for his kid!
那個為了救小孩把劍丟掉的白痴
What did he just do?
剛才是怎麼回事？
You can't get so worked up.
你不該被激怒的
You still lack training, kid.
你的訓練還是不夠，孩子
Damn you!
去你的！
Bjorn, help him up.
表倫，扶他起來
Got it.
好
Boy, I'm hungry.
天啊，我好餓
Alright.
對了
Old man!
叔叔！
I'm hungry for some mutton.
我想吃羊肉
Roasted with herbs.
香草烤羊肉
I've been waiting for this!
這個我等好久了
It's freezing outside. Who's watching the ships?
外面冷死人了
I got lucky. Thorfinn didn't want to switch.
我很幸運，托爾芬不想換班
You mean he's still being a sore loser?
你是說那個輸不起的人？
He's been like that from the beginning.
他從以前就是這樣
He goes there to cool off.
他都去那裡冷靜一下
That ship was his father's to begin with.
那本來就是他爸的船
Just let him be.
隨他去吧
Not bad.
還不錯
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特
Today's duel was impressive!
今天的決鬥真是厲害
Is that so?
是嗎？
At the end, you threw him, didn't you?
你最後把他丟出去了，對吧？
How did you do it?
你是怎麼辦到的？
That was incredible!
太不可思議了！
But Captain, are you sure you want to let a kid like that on your ship?
但是老大
What if he attacks you in your sleep?
他要是趁你睡著時偷襲你怎麼辦？
It's fine.
放心吧
That boy won't do a thing.
那孩子不會做那種事
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
It's because he's still a warrior.
他怎麼說也是個戰士
He wants to win a fight fair and square.
他只想要贏得光明磊落
His past and his pride hold him back.
他的過去和自尊心一直束縛著他
You again, Horda?
又是妳嗎，荷薩蘭特？
You're disrupting everyone!
妳在擾亂大家！
Clean this up now!
快點清乾淨！
How long are you going to act like nobility?
妳要繼續當貴族到什麼時候？
Stand! Get up!
站起來！起來！
You clumsy fool!
笨手笨腳的蠢蛋！
I don't really understand.
我不太懂
If I had to live without pride, I'd probably kill myself.
要是活得沒有尊嚴，我大概會自殺
What?
什麼？
Is that funny?
很好笑嗎？
No, it's not you.
不，我不是在笑你
Look.
你看
What a sorry sight.
真是可笑的景象
I've had it with you! Act like the slave you are!
我受夠妳了，妳不知道妳是奴隸嗎？
A man enslaved by money
一個被錢奴役的傢伙
whipping a slave he bought, so he could act like a master.
拿著鞭子教訓用錢買來的奴隸
He just lacks self-awareness.
一點自知之明都沒有
All men are slaves to something.
其實每個人都被某種東西所奴役
Sulking are we?
你在生悶氣啊？
There, there, crybaby caterpillar.
好了，愛哭的小毛毛蟲
Does it hurt, little one?
會痛嗎，小傢伙？
You want revenge?
你想報仇嗎？
You're my son.
你是我兒子
It's pointless for me to try to dissuade you.
我要你別報仇也沒有用
That's a problem.
問題大了
What should I say?
我該怎麼勸你？
You may have to realize it on your own.
或許你只能自己去體會了
I told you, didn't I?
我不是說過了嗎？
You do not have enemies.
你沒有敵人
No one has enemies.
沒有人有敵人
A true warrior does not need a sword…
真正的戰士不需要劍…
Well…
那個…
Lord Gorm told me to bring you some dinner.
哥魯姆大人叫我送吃的來給你
Hey.
喂
Are you a slave too?
你也是奴隸嗎？
What?
什麼？
It's just that you're eating out here.
因為你在這種地方吃飯
I am a warrior.
我是戰士
Unlike you, I can choose where to have my meals.
和妳不同，我能自己選擇吃飯的地點
Really?
真的嗎？
I feel like you and I are one and the same.
可是我覺得你和我差不多啊
What do I care for a slave's feelings!
我才不在乎奴隸的感受！
If I were you, I'd kill Gorm and escape.
如果我是妳，我會殺死哥魯姆後逃跑
And I'd kill all my pursuers!
追兵也全殺掉！
How awful.
真糟糕
Kill?
殺人？
Then remain a slave for life.
那妳就當一輩子的奴隸吧
That's your choice.
隨便妳
If I ran…
要是我逃跑…
If I ran on and on to the end of the sea,
如果我逃到大海的另一頭
what would I find there?
那裡又會有什麼呢？
There's probably nothing there.
那裡可能什麼都沒有
No matter where I go, it's the same as here.
不管去哪裡都一樣
Only war and slave traders.
只有戰爭和奴隸販子
Far to the west…
遙遠的西方
and beyond the sea…
海的另一邊
is a land called Vinland.
有個名叫文蘭的地方
It is a warm and plentiful place,
那裡很溫暖，是個富饒的地方
so far that slave traders and the flames of war cannot reach it.
是個奴隸買賣和戰火無法觸及的地方
There, no one would pursue you.
在那裡，沒人會去找妳
Does such a place truly exist?
真的有那種地方嗎？
AUGUST 1013 A.D. NEAR JELLING, DENMARK
（西元1013年8月 丹麥，耶林附近）
We are gathering Denmark's finest from every corner of the land.
我們正從丹麥各地集結精英
Additionally, four Jomsviking battalions are hastening to join us.
此外，約姆戰士團的四個大隊 都急著想加入我們
This time, our offensive will go ahead without fail.
這次，我們的攻勢一定會成功
Finally.
終於
Those insolent men of England
英格蘭那些狂妄之徒
will see the power of a king.
將會見識到王者的力量
Yes. All battalions are ready
是，戰士團全體成員都準備好
to fulfill Your Majesty's will to seize England.
為陛下征服英格蘭的大業 付出一己之力
And Canute? Has he come?
庫奴特呢？他來了嗎？
Yes.
是的
His Highness has entered Jelling.
殿下已經到達耶林
He is resting in preparation for the imminent march to battle.
他正在養精蓄銳 為了即將到臨的戰鬥做準備
Your Majesty.
陛下
Will you not reconsider?
您不再考慮一下嗎？
Ragnar.
拉古納爾
Must His Highness Canute accompany the army?
庫奴特殿下一定要同行嗎？
He is a prospective heir to the throne.
他是王位繼承人之一
He must be given a chance to show valor to not fall behind his brother Harald.
必須讓他立功 不能輸給他的兄長哈羅德
But His Highness is fearful and lacks experience on the battlefield.
但殿下很擔心，而且他沒經歷過戰事
Ragnar.
拉古納爾
I, too, am concerned for Canute's welfare.
我也很擔心庫奴特的安全
But as leaders of the Vikings,
但是身為維京人的領導者
we must show valor in order to lead the people.
展現英姿才能獲得人民的支持
We set sail in the morning.
我們早上出航
In August of 1013 A.D.,
西元1013年8月
the main Viking fleet of Denmark commanded by King Sweyn
斯韋恩王率領丹麥維京主力艦隊
began its invasion into the River Humber of northern England.
從英格蘭北部的亨伯河入侵
After forcing the surrender of the five major towns around Gainsborough,
在蓋恩斯伯勒逼迫五大城市的投降後
without losing momentum,
他們勢如破竹
the main army took a land route down south.
主力部隊走陸路南下
They advanced forward while trampling down every region.
一邊進軍，一邊蹂躪各地
However, the steady advance that they believed would continue
他們以為穩定的攻勢將持續下去
stalled upon reaching a certain point…
卻在一個地方暫停了下來
the bustling city of commerce, London.
那就是商業之都，倫敦
OCTOBER 1013 A.D. LONDON, ENGLAND
（西元1013年10月，英格蘭，倫敦）
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Come attack me!
來攻擊我啊！
Isn't this a fun war?
這場戰爭很有趣吧？